{
    "id": "ab23f7b839bd432fb4d10114fe7ff536",
    "title": "Linking Expressions Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I waited for them …………………….. they came.",
            "description": "Till and until are interchangeable.",
            "answers": [
                "till",
                "until",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "757b29e03dd346899ea69d3108efc689"
        },
        {
            "question": "……………………. men sow, so shall they reap.",
            "description": "As is a conjunction like is a preposition. We need a conjunction to connect two clauses. ",
            "answers": [
                "As",
                "Like",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "cd222e960843449cb8a38adbe91a1556"
        },
        {
            "question": "I am as strong ……………………….. you are.",
            "description": "To say that people or things are equal in a particular way, we use the structure as…as…",
            "answers": [
                "like",
                "than",
                "as"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "e448a125bdec4614a46cc5279b2cd6ad"
        },
        {
            "question": "He was …………………….. tired that he could barely stand.",
            "description": "We cannot use a that-clause after very or too. ",
            "answers": [
                "so",
                "very",
                "too"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "c7ab96b18a844f4dadfc80d0ffd5e70d"
        },
        {
            "question": "It is certain …………………… he will be late.",
            "description": "Noun clauses are often introduced by the conjunction that. ",
            "answers": [
                "whether",
                "that",
                "what"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "298dc218082b4897a9792e5844505d08"
        },
        {
            "question": "………………………. a large sum of money, he gave up speculation.",
            "description": "He lost a large sum of money. He gave up gambling. We can combine them with the perfect participle 'having lost'.",
            "answers": [
                "Have lost",
                "Lost",
                "Having lost"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "df16579407f540849cc960f732e850c2"
        },
        {
            "question": "……………………….. he will waste his time is certain.",
            "description": "He will waste his time. That is certain. When we combine them we get: That he will waste his time is certain. ",
            "answers": [
                "That",
                "What",
                "Whether"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "cec5125851694d04baf84dd8ed340b8a"
        },
        {
            "question": "……………………….. he is short-tempered, I like him.",
            "description": "Despite is a preposition however is a transitional adverb although is a conjunction. We need a conjunction to connect two clauses. ",
            "answers": [
                "Despite",
                "However",
                "Although"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "046fb2e67bdb4cd8a2c9aa9d02c7974b"
        },
        {
            "question": "Ask the guard …………………………. it is time for the train to start?",
            "description": "Indirect yes/no questions can be introduced by if or whether.",
            "answers": [
                "whether",
                "if",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "afc98912e4684229877340c44072328b"
        },
        {
            "question": "……………………. I know all the facts, I cannot help you.",
            "description": "Unless mean if not. ",
            "answers": [
                "Unless",
                "Until",
                "If"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "106777ef079a40d48ad99c926d9e507b"
        },
        {
            "question": "The votes on each side …………………… equal, the chairman gave his casting vote against the resolution.",
            "description": "When we split the sentence we get:\r\nThe votes on each side were equal. The chairman gave his casting vote against the resolution.\r\nWhen we combine these two clauses into a simple sentence, we use the participle ‘being’.\r\n",
            "answers": [
                "was",
                "were",
                "been",
                "being"
            ],
            "correct": 3,
            "id": "67d883046b254639b328fde174030126"
        },
        {
            "question": "……………………. tired, he stopped working.",
            "description": "When we split clauses, we get: He felt tired He stopped working. We can combine them with the present participle 'feeling'.",
            "answers": [
                "Felt",
                "Feeling",
                "Having felt"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "dfd5a81fc04e49e98102c1107721fa61"
        }
    ]
}